<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-24T12:06:26-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chase Leinart’s Blog</title><subtitle>I&apos;m a software engineer by profession. Some of my interests include linguistics, reverse engineering, emacs, and good food. Any opinions expressed are solely my own.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Smoked Salmon Bagel Review - Earth’s Harvest in Dover, NH</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/24/earths-harvest.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smoked Salmon Bagel Review - Earth’s Harvest in Dover, NH" /><published>2022-08-24T11:44:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-24T11:44:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/24/earths-harvest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/24/earths-harvest.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey there friends! It’s time for another salmon bagel review. Today I sampled the Smoked Salmon Bagel from Earth’s Harvest in Dover, NH.</p>

<p>On the whole, Earth’s Harvest has a high quality and intriguing menu for Dover, if a bit expensive. The virtue of a Banh Mi sandwich is that it’s a cheap yummy bite…not a $15 luxury.</p>

<p>If you take a gander at my receipt, you won’t see the price for a Smoked Salmon Bagel from Earth’s Harvest, but I’ll simply tell you that it was $12. That’s to say, close to 50% more than our friends over at Bubby’s. One could get 3 Lox Sandwiches at Bubby’s for only a few more shekels than 2 Smoked Salmon Bagels at Earth’s Harvest….</p>

<p>Another thing - our previous two reviews have been for lox bagels whereas this is smoked salmon. Smoked salmon and lox are both cured or brined, but as the name suggests, smoked salmon is then smoked afterwards.</p>

<p><img src="/images/earth_harvest_receipt.jpg" alt="Earth's Harvest Receipt" /></p>

<p>As you can see, I opted for an everything bagel today. I think between plain and everything that I made the better choice.</p>

<p><img src="/images/earth_harvest_whole_bagel.jpg" alt="Bagel View" /></p>

<p>This one differed from Bubby’s and Loxsmith in the toppings. We have red onion, sprouts, cucumber, capers, and of course smoked salmon, and cream cheese.</p>

<p><img src="/images/earth_harvest_cross_section.jpg" alt="Bagel Cross Section" /></p>

<p>I was interested to newly try and review this one, because I’ve had it several times in the past, and had certain concerns on several of those visits. In the past, I often found that the volume of sprouts on the bagel has been overwhelming. Several times during prior visits, half or more of the sprouts would fall onto the plate from the imbalance of the sandwich. I’m relieved to say that this sandwich wasn’t overburdend with sprouts. In spite of that, I do have a few gripes with this sandwich today. The most notable is the toasting of the bagel - it’s nearly absent. The bagel, apart from being warm, is nearly indistinguishable from an off the shelf untoasted bagel, barring the house-made quality. The doughiness and dryness of the bagel weaken its value in the sandwich tremendously, in my opinion. Additionally, not all toppings were as represented as I would have liked. I initially suspected that the sandwich didn’t include capers, but found some a few bites in.</p>

<p><img src="/images/earth_harvest_in_half_on_plate.jpg" alt="Bagel on Plate" /></p>

<h1 id="rating-69100">Rating: 69/100</h1>

<p>I love salmon, so it’s hard to dislike any employment of the fish, but I think this sandwich had a few flaws. Were the bagel better toasted and the toppings more evenly distributed, the sandwich would have been greatly improved. I’ll probably revisit Earth’s Harvest in a future review to see if anything is changed.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey there friends! It’s time for another salmon bagel review. Today I sampled the Smoked Salmon Bagel from Earth’s Harvest in Dover, NH.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lox Bagel Review - Loxsmith Bagel Co. in Dover, NH</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/17/loxsmith-bagels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lox Bagel Review - Loxsmith Bagel Co. in Dover, NH" /><published>2022-08-17T12:23:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-17T12:23:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/17/loxsmith-bagels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/17/loxsmith-bagels.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey there folks. I’m back at the salmon bagel reviews again. This time, we’re trying out “The Classic”, the flagship bagel from the cleverly-named Loxsmith Bagel Co. in Dover, NH.</p>

<p>I live in walking distance from Loxsmith Bagels, so it’s immediately appealing as a destination. I frankly haven’t tried many things on their menu apart from the lox bagel, which is fine because that’s what this is all about.</p>

<p>If you take a gander at my receipt, you’ll see that The Classic will set you back $9.50. Maybe a little pricey in my opinion, but eating out in general is becoming much more costly, so hardly unexpected.</p>

<p><img src="/images/loxsmith_bagel_receipt.jpg" alt="Bubby's Menu" /></p>

<p>The sandwich doesn’t have a generous portion of salmon, but it also doesn’t skimp out. The sandwich includes cream cheese, capers, and onion. I actually think it’s pretty well balenced</p>

<p><img src="/images/loxsmith_bagel_halves.jpg" alt="Bagel View" /></p>

<p>The sandwich itself is pretty good. I don’t think any one ingredient stood out particularly. The portion sizes were appropriate and contributed to the balance of the sandwich. I’ve certainly had a sandwich before that is so loaded that half the filling spills out while eating. That wasn’t an issue here. The salmon wasn’t overpowering, but blended in nicely, and was contrasted by the brine and sharpness of the capers and onion. I got mine on a sesame bagel, which  seems to be a pattern for me - maybe in future reviews I’ll try poppyseed. The bagel was actually toasted nicely. The inside of the bagel was soft and flexible, contrasting well with the crispy exterior.</p>

<h1 id="rating-83100">Rating: 83/100</h1>

<p>Overall, a very nice sandwich. That seems it should be a given for a place called Loxsmith Bagels. I would certainly order it again.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey there folks. I’m back at the salmon bagel reviews again. This time, we’re trying out “The Classic”, the flagship bagel from the cleverly-named Loxsmith Bagel Co. in Dover, NH.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lox Bagel Review - Bubby’s Bagel &amp;amp; Deli</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/07/24/bubbys-bagels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lox Bagel Review - Bubby’s Bagel &amp;amp; Deli" /><published>2022-07-24T20:51:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-24T20:51:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food/2022/07/24/bubbys-bagels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/07/24/bubbys-bagels.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey you shitheads. I fucking love bagels with smoked salmon or lox. Maybe you think lox is the same thing, but you’re wrong. Go google it.</p>

<p>Anyway. I’m going to eat as many bagels with some type of salmon on them and write reviews on them.</p>

<p>My first review will be for the Lox Sandwich available at Bubby’s Bagels and Deli in Dover, NH. What can be said of Bubby’s? Well, they’re located inside the train station in Dover, NH. I personally think that’s pretty cool. They also have tasty rugelach, which I haven’t found anywhere else on the NH Seacoast.</p>

<p>If you take a gander at their menu, you’ll see that the Lox Sandwich comes in at $8.25. I don’t think that’s too bad for this type of sandwich these days.</p>

<p><img src="/images/bubbys_menu.jpg" alt="Bubby's Menu" /></p>

<p>Taking a look at the interior of the sandwich, you can see that the salmon portion you get is pretty generous. The sandwich includes cream cheese, tomato, capers, and onion. In my mind, that is the perfect set of toppings for a sandwich like this. Not too much - not too little.</p>

<p><img src="/images/bubbys_bagel_halves.jpg" alt="Bagel View" /></p>

<p>The sandwich itself is great. The onion isn’t so strong as to skew the flavor profile, the capers add some nice brine, and the salmon has a bright taste. I got mine on a sesame bagel, which I think is a good choice. The bagel was toasted just the right amount. Not so little as to make me question whether they toasted it at all, and not so much as to make it crispy or crunchy.</p>

<h1 id="rating-91100">Rating: 91/100</h1>

<p>I’ve had other lox/smoked salmon bagels in Dover, but haven’t reviewed them yet. I’ll cut to the chase and suggest that Bubby’s has my favorite in town, unless the others I intend to later review have since upped their game. Keep up the good work.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey you shitheads. I fucking love bagels with smoked salmon or lox. Maybe you think lox is the same thing, but you’re wrong. Go google it.]]></summary></entry></feed>