<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-17T22:49:12-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chase Leinart’s Blog</title><subtitle>I&apos;m a software engineer by profession. Some of my interests include linguistics, reverse engineering, emacs, and good food. Any opinions expressed are solely my own.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Lox Bagel Review - Loxsmith Bagel Co. in Dover, NH</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/17/loxsmith-bagels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lox Bagel Review - Loxsmith Bagel Co. in Dover, NH" /><published>2022-08-17T12:23:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-17T12:23:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/17/loxsmith-bagels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/08/17/loxsmith-bagels.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey there folks. I’m back at the salmon bagel reviews again. This time, we’re trying out “The Classic”, the flagship bagel from the cleverly-named Loxsmith Bagel Co. in Dover, NH.</p>

<p>I live in walking distance from Loxsmith Bagels, so it’s immediately appealing as a destination. I frankly haven’t tried many things on their menu apart from the lox bagel, which is fine because that’s what this is all about.</p>

<p>If you take a gander at my receipt, you’ll see that The Classic will set you back $9.50. Maybe a little pricey in my opinion, but eating out in general is becoming much more costly, so hardly unexpected.</p>

<p><img src="/images/loxsmith_bagel_receipt.jpg" alt="Bubby's Menu" /></p>

<p>The sandwich doesn’t have a generous portion of salmon, but it also doesn’t skimp out. The sandwich includes cream cheese, capers, and onion. I actually think it’s pretty well balenced</p>

<p><img src="/images/loxsmith_bagel_halves.jpg" alt="Bagel View" /></p>

<p>The sandwich itself is pretty good. I don’t think any one ingredient stood out particularly. The portion sizes were appropriate and contributed to the balance of the sandwich. I’ve certainly had a sandwich before that is so loaded that half the filling spills out while eating. That wasn’t an issue here. The salmon wasn’t overpowering, but blended in nicely, and was contrasted by the brine and sharpness of the capers and onion. I got mine on a sesame bagel, which  seems to be a pattern for me - maybe in future reviews I’ll try poppyseed. The bagel was actually toasted nicely. The inside of the bagel was soft and flexible, contrasting well with the crispy exterior.</p>

<h1 id="rating-83100">Rating: 83/100</h1>

<p>Overall, a very nice sandwich. That seems it should be a given for a place called Loxsmith Bagels. I would certainly order it again.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey there folks. I’m back at the salmon bagel reviews again. This time, we’re trying out “The Classic”, the flagship bagel from the cleverly-named Loxsmith Bagel Co. in Dover, NH.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lox Bagel Review - Bubby’s Bagel &amp;amp; Deli</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/07/24/bubbys-bagels.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lox Bagel Review - Bubby’s Bagel &amp;amp; Deli" /><published>2022-07-24T20:51:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-24T20:51:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/food/2022/07/24/bubbys-bagels</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/food/2022/07/24/bubbys-bagels.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey you shitheads. I fucking love bagels with smoked salmon or lox. Maybe you think lox is the same thing, but you’re wrong. Go google it.</p>

<p>Anyway. I’m going to eat as many bagels with some type of salmon on them and write reviews on them.</p>

<p>My first review will be for the Lox Sandwich available at Bubby’s Bagels and Deli in Dover, NH. What can be said of Bubby’s? Well, they’re located inside the train station in Dover, NH. I personally think that’s pretty cool. They also have tasty rugelach, which I haven’t found anywhere else on the NH Seacoast.</p>

<p>If you take a gander at their menu, you’ll see that the Lox Sandwich comes in at $8.25. I don’t think that’s too bad for this type of sandwich these days.</p>

<p><img src="/images/bubbys_menu.jpg" alt="Bubby's Menu" /></p>

<p>Taking a look at the interior of the sandwich, you can see that the salmon portion you get is pretty generous. The sandwich includes cream cheese, tomato, capers, and onion. In my mind, that is the perfect set of toppings for a sandwich like this. Not too much - not too little.</p>

<p><img src="/images/bubbys_bagel_halves.jpg" alt="Bagel View" /></p>

<p>The sandwich itself is great. The onion isn’t so strong as to skew the flavor profile, the capers add some nice brine, and the salmon has a bright taste. I got mine on a sesame bagel, which I think is a good choice. The bagel was toasted just the right amount. Not so little as to make me question whether they toasted it at all, and not so much as to make it crispy or crunchy.</p>

<h1 id="rating-91100">Rating: 91/100</h1>

<p>I’ve had other lox/smoked salmon bagels in Dover, but haven’t reviewed them yet. I’ll cut to the chase and suggest that Bubby’s has my favorite in town, unless the others I intend to later review have since upped their game. Keep up the good work.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey you shitheads. I fucking love bagels with smoked salmon or lox. Maybe you think lox is the same thing, but you’re wrong. Go google it.]]></summary></entry></feed>